Guide to the Robert Maynard Hutchins Papers 1884-2000
University of Chicago Library
- Series X: Writings
  - Subseries 4: Speeches
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, A-B, April – July 1941 (Box 382, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, C, March – March 1941 (Box 383, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, D-G, March – May 1941 (Box 383, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, H-Hottendorf, March – May 1941 (Box 383, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, Howell-J, April – May 1941 (Box 383, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, K-L, April – October 1941 (Box 383, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, M, March – June 1941 (Box 383, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, N-Q, April – August 1941 (Box 384, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, R-S, March – May 1941 (Box 384, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members that received special replies, T-Z, March – September 1941 (Box 384, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members, Critical letters, A-Z, March – April 1941 (Box 384, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members, Anonymous letters, March – April 1941 (Box 384, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members, Unanswered, March 1941 – December 1943 (Box 384, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members, General [1/3], March – November 1941 (Box 384, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members, General [2/3], February 1941 (Box 384, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "The Proposition is Peace" (30 March 1941) with audience members, General [3/3], January – March 1941 (Box 385, Folder 1)
    - Radio Speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941), Press Release, 24 January 1941 (Box 385, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, A-Boet, May 1940 – February 1941 (Box 385, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, Bof-B, January – May 1941 (Box 385, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience member that received special replies s, C-E, January – October 1941 (Box 385, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, F-G, January – February 1941 (Box 385, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, H, January – May 1941 (Box 385, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, I-L, January – February 1941 (Box 386, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, M, January – June 1941 (Box 386, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, N-P, January – July 1941 (Box 386, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, Q-Smith, January – October 1941 (Box 386, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, Spoffard-T, January – May 1941 (Box 386, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special replies, U-Z, January – March 1941 (Box 386, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received special form replies, A-Z, January 1941 (Box 387, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, A-Bishop, January – February 1941 (Box 387, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, Black-B, January 1941 (Box 387, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, C, January – February 1941 (Box 387, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, D-E, January – February 1941 (Box 387, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, F-G, January – February 1941 (Box 387, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, H, January – March 1941 (Box 387, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, I-K, January 1941 (Box 388, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, L, January – March 1941 (Box 388, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, M-McWilliams, January 1941 (Box 388, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, Mead-N, January 1941 (Box 388, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, O-R, January – February 1941 (Box 388, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, S-Smiley, January 1941 (Box 388, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, Smith-T, January 1941 (Box 389, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.1, U-Z, January – February 1941 (Box 389, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.2, A-G, January – March 1941 (Box 389, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.2, H-R, January – March 1941 (Box 389, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.2, S-Z, January – June 1941 (Box 389, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, A-B, January – February 1941 (Box 390, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, C-D, January – February 1941 (Box 390, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, E-G, January 1941 (Box 390, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, H, January – February 1941 (Box 390, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, I-K, January 1941 (Box 390, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, L, January – February 1941 (Box 390, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, M, January – March 1941 (Box 391, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, N-P, January – February 1941 (Box 391, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, Q-R, January 1941 (Box 391, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, S, January 1941 (Box 391, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members that received reply no.3, T-Z, January – February 1941 (Box 391, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941), letters concerning the Daughters of the American Revolution, A-Z, January – February 1941 (Box 391, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, critical letters, A-K, January – February 1941 (Box 391, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, critical letters, L-P, January – February 1941 (Box 392, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, critical letters, Q-Z, January – February 1941 (Box 392, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, Unanswered [1 of 2], January – February 1941 (Box 392, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, Unanswered [2 of 2], January – February 1941 (Box 392, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, Anonymous, January – March 1941 (Box 392, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, no return address [1 of 2], January – February 1941 (Box 392, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding radio speech "America and the War" (23 January 1941) with audience members, no return address [2 of 2], January – February 1941 (Box 392, Folder 7)
    - Log of Correspondence regarding radio speeches "America and the War," "The Proposition is Peace," and "Town Hall Speech," 1941 (Box 393, Folder 1)
    - Index of carbon copies of outgoing Correspondence regarding radio speeches "America and the War," "The Proposition is Peace," and "Town Hall Speech" [1/2], 1941 (Box 393, Folder 2)
    - Index of carbon copies of outgoing Correspondence regarding radio speeches "America and the War," "The Proposition is Peace," and "Town Hall Speech" [2/2], 1941 (Box 393, Folder 3)
    - Carbon copies of outgoing Correspondence regarding radio speeches "America and the War," "The Proposition is Peace," and "Town Hall Speech" [1/2], 1941 (Box 393, Folder 4)
    - Carbon copies of outgoing Correspondence regarding radio speeches "America and the War," "The Proposition is Peace," and "Town Hall Speech" [2/2], 1941 (Box 393, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 5: Engagements
    - Yale Class of 1921 (June 1921), 1921 (Box 393, Folder 6)
    - "Our Contemporary Ancestors" (November 1921), 1921 (Box 393, Folder 7)
    - "Campus Relevancies," 1921 (Box 393, Folder 8)
    - "The South and Yale Today," 1921 (Box 393, Folder 9)
    - Stanford Men's Club (January 23, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 10)
    - Class Agents Dinner (January 25, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 11)
    - Class of '96 Dinner Speech (January 27, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 12)
    - Wolf's Head (Yale) Dinner (January 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 13)
    - Boston Yale Club Alumni (February 14, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 14)
    - New Haven Association of Credit Men (March 1, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 15)
    - Alpha Delta Phi (March 6, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 16)
    - Yale Alumni – Hartford (March 7, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 17)
    - Milford Men's Club (March 20, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 18)
    - Fairfield County Association (April 9, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 19)
    - Yale Law Journal Dinner (April 21, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 20)
    - New Haven Alumni Association (April 24, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 21)
    - Yale Class of 1921 (April 28, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 22)
    - Connecticut Association of Credit Men (May 17, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 23)
    - Yale Alumni Day Luncheon (June 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 24)
    - Philadelphia Radio (December 4, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 25)
    - Alpha Delta Phi (December 18, 1923), 1923 (Box 393, Folder 26)
    - Brooks Club, Trinity Church (January 14, 1924), 1924 (Box 393, Folder 27)
    - Yale Class of 1892 Reunion (January 25, 1924), 1924 (Box 393, Folder 28)
    - Yale Alumni – Class of 1908 (February 1, 1924) – Slip Only, undated (Box 393, Folder 29)
    - Essex County (March 28, 1924), 1924 (Box 393, Folder 30)
    - Hotchkiss College Commencement (May 1924), 1924 (Box 393, Folder 31)
    - Yale Alumni University Day (June 1924), 1924 (Box 394, Folder 1)
    - New Haven Lawn Club (November 18, 1924), 1924 (Box 394, Folder 2)
    - Essex County/Plainfield, 1924 (Box 394, Folder 3)
    - Headmasters' Associations – Introducing Admiral Sims (February 6, 1925), 1925 (Box 394, Folder 4)
    - Yale Law School Alumni (May 4, 1925), 1925 (Box 394, Folder 5)
    - Yale Alumni University Day Luncheon (June 1925), 1925 (Box 394, Folder 6)
    - Yale-Oxford Debate (October 23, 1925), 1925 (Box 394, Folder 7)
    - "Equitable Ejectment" (December 30, 1925), 1925 (Box 394, Folder 8)
    - Hotchkiss College Commencement (May 2, 1926), 1926 (Box 394, Folder 9)
    - "Evidence and the Scientific Method" (December 1926), 1926 (Box 394, Folder 10)
    - Yale Alumni (December 1926), 1926 (Box 394, Folder 11)
    - Yale-in-China, 1926 (Box 394, Folder 12)
    - New York Oberlin Alumni (January 1927), 1927 (Box 394, Folder 13)
    - Hotchkiss College Commencement (June 1927), 1927 (Box 394, Folder 14)
    - "An Institute of Procedure at Yale University," 1927 (Box 394, Folder 15)
    - "American Education in 1928" (January 16, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 16)
    - "Legal Education" (January 28, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 17)
    - Oberlin Alumni of Boston (April 2, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 18)
    - Harvard Law Review (April 2, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 19)
    - Berea College Commencement (April 7, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 20)
    - "Connecticut and the Yale Law School" (April 20, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 21)
    - American Law Institute (April 28, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 22)
    - "Experiments in Legal Education at Yale" (April 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 23)
    - "American Education in 1928" (May 8, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 24)
    - Yale Law School Alumni – Welcome Address (June 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 25)
    - Community Chest (November 9, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 26)
    - "Legal Research in West Virginia" (November 28, 1928), 1928 (Box 394, Folder 27)
    - "Modern Movements in Legal Education" (December 27, 1928) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 394, Folder 28)
    - "Fraude's Life of Bunyan," 1928 (Box 394, Folder 29)
    - Yale Alumni, Twin Cities, 1928 (Box 394, Folder 30)
    - Cleveland Real Estate Board, (February 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 31)
    - "Law and Medicine at Yale" (March 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 32)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Banquet (March 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 33)
    - "The Current of Legal Education" (April 4, 1929) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 394, Folder 34)
    - "Legal Education" (June 8, 1929) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 394, Folder 35)
    - University of Chicago Convocation (June 11, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 36)
    - Alpha Delta Phi, (October 4, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 37)
    - Lafayette College Commencement (June 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 38)
    - University of Chicago Faculty Homecoming Dinner (October 7, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 39)
    - Yale Club Dinner (October 18, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 40)
    - Union League Club October 29, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 41)
    - Commercial Club of Chicago (November 8, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 42)
    - Inaugural Address (University of Chicago Presidency) (November 19, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 43)
    - University of Chicago – Delegate Luncheon (November 19, 1929) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 394, Folder 44)
    - Inauguration Dinner Speech (November 19, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 45)
    - University of Chicago Student Meeting (November 20, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 46)
    - Sunny Gymnasium Dedication (November 26, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 47)
    - The Standard Club (December 1, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 48)
    - Teachers' Union of Chicago (December 2, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 49)
    - Dedication of George Herbert Jones Laboratory (December 16, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 50)
    - Dedication of Social Science Building (December 16, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 51)
    - Dedication Dinner for Social Science Building (December 16, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 52)
    - "About Admissions and Training" (December 17, 1929), 1929 (Box 394, Folder 53)
    - Trustees' Dinner (January 8, 1930), 1930 (Box 394, Folder 54)
    - Alumni Dinner Speech (January 22, 1930), 1930 (Box 394, Folder 55)
    - "Organized Study of Behavior" (January 19, 1930), 1930 (Box 394, Folder 56)
    - "The University and the Commercial World" (February 5, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 1)
    - Medical and Nursing Groups (February 17, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 2)
    - Harvard University Club (February 21, 1930) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 395, Folder 3)
    - Alumni Dinner (February 27, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 4)
    - "Child Study and Parent Education" (March 7, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 5)
    - "The University and the Individual" (April 3, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 6)
    - "The Press and Education" (April 18, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 7)
    - "Institute of Human Relations" (April 28, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 8)
    - "The Trend of Education" (May 2, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 9)
    - "Teaching Today" (May 28, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 10)
    - "Teaching Today" (May 29, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 11)
    - University of Chicago Alumni Meeting (June 7, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 12)
    - "Education versus Research" (June 10, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 13)
    - Williams College Commencement (June 16, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 14)
    - "Education in Independence" (June 18, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 15)
    - "Education in the Arts" (June 20, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 16)
    - Jane Addams's 70th Birthday (September 6, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 17)
    - University of Chicago Faculty Homecoming Dinner (October 6, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 18)
    - Yale Club of Chicago (October 17, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 19)
    - Conference of Major Institutions (October 22, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 20)
    - "The Situation in Education (University of Utopia)," (October 30, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 21)
    - Association of High School Principals (November 20, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 22)
    - Cleveland Phi Beta Kappa, et al. (December 5, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 23)
    - University of Chicago Convocation (December 23, 1930), 1930 (Box 395, Folder 24)
    - "Education and the University of Chicago" (January 2, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 25)
    - Trustees' Dinner (January 8, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 26)
    - "The University in 1931" (March 6, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 27)
    - Collier's Hour, NBC Radio (March 8, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 28)
    - "Importance of Irish Culture" (March 17, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 29)
    - "The Chicago Plan" (March 19, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 30)
    - Association of Doctors of Philosophy (April 14, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 31)
    - Michelson Memorial Service (May 18, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 32)
    - "New Atlantis" (June 1, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 33)
    - "New Lessons from the New Atlantis" (June 16, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 34)
    - Dedication of Gertrude Dunn Hicks Building (June 22, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 35)
    - Norman Wait Harris Memorial Foundation (June 22, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 36)
    - "The Upper Divisions of the University of Chicago" (July 9, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 37)
    - Freshman Assembly (September 24, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 38)
    - Homecoming Dinner (October 5, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 39)
    - Yale Club of Chicago (October 16, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 40)
    - "The Chicago Plan and Graduate Study" (November 13, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 41)
    - Philadelphia Yale Club (November 18, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 42)
    - "The Tenure of Professors"/"The Professor Pays" (November 27, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 43)
    - Dedication of the Oriental Institute (December 5, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 44)
    - "The University of Chicago – to the Students" (December 20, 1931), 1931 (Box 395, Folder 45)
    - "Economics and Psychology by Radio" (January 2, 1932), 1932 (Box 395, Folder 46)
    - Trustees' Dinner to Faculties (January 14, 1932), 1932 (Box 395, Folder 47)
    - Kansas City Chamber of Commerce (January 27, 1932) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 395, Folder 48)
    - "The New Plan" (January 27, 1932), 1932 (Box 395, Folder 49)
    - Humanities Discussion Group (January 31, 1932) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 396, Folder 1)
    - "The New Plan" (February 9, 1932), 1932 (Box 396, Folder 2)
    - Alumni of Washington, D.C. (February 24, 1932), 1932 (Box 396, Folder 3)
    - "Education as a National Enterprise" (February 25, 1932), 1932 (Box 396, Folder 4)
    - Goethe Centennial (March 8, 1932), 1932 (Box 396, Folder 5)
    - Dedication of Boys' Gym (March 3, 1932) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 396, Folder 6)
    - "The New Plan" (March 16, 1932), 1932 (Box 396, Folder 7)
    - Annual Banquet of U of C Press (April 21, 1932) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 396, Folder 8)
    - "The New Plan" (April 25, 1932) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 396, Folder 9)
    - "The New Plan" (May 4, 1932) -- Slip Only, undated (Box 396, Folder 10)
    - "The New Plan" (May 17, 1932), 1932 (Box 396, Folder 11)